<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Puppetlabs Podcasts</title>
		<link>http://puppetlabs.com/resources/podcasts</link>
		<description>All Puppet Labs podcasts</description>
		<atom:link href="http://puppetlabs.com/resources/podcasts"
			rel="self" />
		<docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
		<generator>python-feedgen</generator>
		<image>
			<url>http://puppetlabs.com/sites/default/files/puppet-labs-podcast-icon.png</url>
			<title>Puppetlabs Podcasts</title>
			<link>http://puppetlabs.com/resources/podcasts</link>
		</image>
		<language>en</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 23:35:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<itunes:category text="Technology">
			<itunes:category text="Podcasting" />
		</itunes:category>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Puppetboard | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>We would like to use our podcasts to showcase more cool,
				new projects from the community, so last week Hunter Haugen and Dawn
				Foster talked to Daniele Sluijters (a.k.a. "daenney") about his
				newly released Puppetboard project.
				Just last week, Daniele announced Puppetboard on the puppet-users list,
				humbly beginning,  "it’s a lovely grey and rainy day here in the
				Dutch summer, as good a day as any to release a new little project."
				Puppetboard is a web interface to PuppetDB aiming to replace the
				reporting functionality of Puppet Dashboard. Currently, Puppetboard
				can show you all the info that PuppetDB can show you: a list of
				nodes and all known facts for each node in your infrastructure. You
				can drill down into them by fact, node, and run reports.
				This is so new that it comes with some significant caveats and some of
				the code is experimental, so contributions and bug reports are
				welcome!
				Daniele will be at PuppetConf starting on Wednesday at Developer Day. Track
				him down at the conference to learn more about Puppetboard.
				See the rest of the podcasts.


				Attend PuppetConf, our annual operations conference at the Fairmont in San
				Francisco on August 22 and 23, and come a day early for Developer
				Day!
				Find a local Puppet User Group or start one in your city
				Visit our community Ask site to get answers and advice for using Puppet.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-puppetboard</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode019-2013-08-13-PuppetBoard.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Puppet</title>
			<description>Florian Haas, CEO, Principal Consultant from Hastexo
				joined Chris Hoge, OpenStack Developer for Puppet Labs, and Dawn
				Foster, Community Lead at Puppet Labs for a discussion during OSCON
				on the love affair between OpenStack and Puppet.
				"The reason why we find Puppet particularly interesting and appealing,"
				says Florian, "is that when we look at all these tools, Puppet has a
				massive mindshare ... there's some very interesting work that has
				been done there."
				At Puppet Labs we've been maintaining a set of modules that allow you
				to deploy a whole OpenStack system with Puppet, but it's part of a
				much larger body of contributors. The modules are a community
				effort, developed under the OpenStack StackForge community.
				The OpenStack Tour de Force tutorial during OSCON used these modules as
				part of KickStack. KickStack is a custom deployment wrapper built on
				the Puppet Labs OpenStack modules, which enables installation of an
				Openstack cloud in as little as 20 minutes
				Looking to get some more OpenStack and Puppet goodness?  Florian Haas from
				Hastexo is holding a class on deploying OpenStack with Puppet in
				Portland. Register now to attend Puppet Cloud Jumpstart for
				OpenStack.
				At Developer Day, the day before PuppetConf, we'll devote one of the
				many hacker tables to OpenStack. During PuppetConf  there are more
				OpenStack talks than I can list here.  See you then!
				Attend PuppetConf, our annual operations conference at the Fairmont in San
				Francisco on August 22 and 23, and come a day early for Developer
				Day!
				Find a local Solutions: Puppet and OpenStack
				Blog Post: Puppet OpenStack modules 2.0 released to ForgePuppet User
				Group
				Find a local Puppet User Group or start one in your city
				Visit our community Ask site to get answers and advice for using Puppet.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-puppet-heart-openstack</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode018-2013-08-08-OpenStack.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Are You Testing Your Puppet Modules? | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>In this week's Puppet Podcast, I'm joined by Ryan
				Coleman, product manager for the Puppet Forge, and module
				engineering team members Ashley Penney and Hunter Haugen. They dive
				into an exploration of the module testing frameworks the Puppet
				Forge team uses.
				What happens when you submit a patch to a module maintained by Puppet
				Labs? Why bother testing your Puppet modules at all?
				Learn the answers to these questions, as well as the value of unit
				testing a module with rspec-puppet and integration testing with
				rspec-system, the tools available to make sure your manifests pass a
				syntax test, and how to take advantage of real-world data from
				Facter during testing.
				Listen to the Puppet Forge team pretend for your benefit that they are bad
				at their jobs, and don't believe a word of it!
				See the rest of the podcasts.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-are-you-testing-your-puppet-modules</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode020-2013-09-10-Module-Testing.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Ben Kero Tells Us "How to Use Puppet Like an Adult" |
				Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>We've been dusting off some audio from OSCON in July,
				and we found this gem for your listening pleasure.
				Kent Bye, videographer &amp; media maven at Puppet Labs, took some time
				out of his busy schedule at OSCON to interview Ben Kero, senior
				sysadmin at Mozilla. They spent some time talking about how Ben and
				the rest of the ops team there use Puppet.
				Ben also talked about his session at OSCON, "How to Use Puppet Like an
				Adult," which he co-presented with fellow Mozillian, Daniel Maher.
				If you missed their talk, you can still have a look through their
				slides.
				A huge thanks to Ben and Kent for doing this, and we hope you enjoy
				the podcast!
				See the rest of the podcasts.
				Find a local Puppet User Group or start one in your city
				Visit our community Ask site to get answers and advice for using Puppet
				How to use Puppet like an adult
				Read about featured community member Dustin Mitchell from Mozilla</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-ben-kero-tells-us-how-use-puppet-adult</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode021-2013-10-09-Mozilla-Puppet-Best-Practices.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Using MCollective for Orchestration | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>We recently sat down with Devon Peters, a tools engineer
				at Jive Software to talk about how they use MCollective for
				orchestration along with Puppet to manage their infrastructure. You
				might remember Devon from his recent PuppetConf talk, "Intro to
				Systems Orchestration with MCollective." We were joined by Pieter
				Loubser and Richard Clamp from the MCollective engineering team here
				at Puppet Labs to talk about a wide variety of orchestration topics.
				This was a fun podcast because we talked about some of the
				performance problems Jive Software has faced in the past, along with
				how the team here at Puppet Labs is working closely with Jive
				Software to improve MCollective performance, which will benefit a
				lot of other companies as well. We also talked about the future of
				MCollective and other things we are doing to improve the product.
				If you are curious and want to learn more, you can check out our new
				and improved MCollective documentation or watch Devon's PuppetConf
				talk, "Intro to Systems Orchestration with MCollective."  You can
				also join us in the community on the MCollective-Users Group or in
				the #mcollective IRC channel on Freenode to ask questions or just
				learn more about how people are using MCollective.
				See the rest of the podcasts.
				Learn More
				Find a local Puppet User Group or start one in your city
				Visit our community Ask site to get answers and advice for using Puppet
				PuppetConf talk:  Intro to Systems Orchestration with MCollective
				Talk to us on the MCollective-Users Group or in the #mcollective IRC
				channel on Freenode
				Read the new and improved MCollective documentation</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-using-mcollective</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode022-2013-10-15-Using-MCollective.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: The New Pro Puppet | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>This week on the Puppet Podcast, authors William Van
				Hevelingen and Spencer Krum join Puppet Community team Dawn Foster
				and Kara Sowles to give us some insight into the upcoming new
				edition of the book Pro Puppet. The third author, Mozilla sysadmin
				Ben Kero, wasn't able to join us.
				The first three chapters of the new Pro Puppet will be focused on
				anyone setting up Puppet for the first time. The rest of the book
				goes deeper, including how to run Puppet without a master, how to
				get your workflow down, an updated section on the MCollective
				orchestration engine, and an entire chapter dedicated to Hiera.


				The original Pro Puppet was written by James Turnbull and Jeff McCune
				and published by Apress in 2011, so it was overdue for an update.
				Listen to how Spencer, William, and Ben ended up writing the book -
				involving a piece of misplaced spam mail - and what book is coming
				up next.
				The new Pro Puppet will be available Nov. 20th on Amazon.com, and you
				can pre-order your copy now!
				 </description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-new-pro-puppet</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode022-2013-10-30-Pro-Puppet-Book.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Google Compute Engine and Puppet | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>In the latest Puppet Podcast, Puppet Community Lead Dawn
				Foster is joined by Eric Johnson, program manager of the Google
				Compute Engine team and Aaron Armstrong, an engineering manager at
				Puppet Labs.
				Last Tuesday, Google announced that its Google Compute Engine is now
				generally available to the public. Listen in to this podcast to hear
				Eric, Aaron and Dawn discuss and explore the integrations between
				Google Cloud Platform and Puppet.
				GCP is a collection of services created using Google's experience
				scaling and supporting their own services: platform-as-a-service and
				infrastructure-as-a-service options, storage solutions and a range
				of other services and developer tools.
				In Puppet Enterprise 3.1, we updated our cloud provisioner to work
				natively with Google Compute Engine, and there's now a node type for
				GCE. Watch the video below to see how you can spin up and interact
				with Google Compute instances directly from the command line.
				Google is also committed to helping make sure that its Puppet modules are
				kept up to date to take advantage of the full power of GCE. Eric
				says,
				"Google is committed to providing support for Puppet users. So we'll be
				contributing support for both GCE_Compute and Node_GCE to ensure
				that it's updated to take advantage of the latest features that GCE
				is releasing."
				Eric helped to update the GCE compute module, which offers Puppet users
				the opportunity to integrate GCE and Puppet. You can create
				additional persistent disks, networks and firewall rules, and set up
				a load balancer. Aaron notes that employees within Puppet Labs are
				particularly excited at how fast it is to provision new nodes on
				GCE, as well as the more granular, per-minute billing that's
				available after the first 10 minutes.
				See the rest of the podcasts.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-google-compute-engine-and-puppet</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode024-2013-12-03-Google-Compute-Engine-and-Puppet.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: DevOps &amp; Cloud Automation at Puppet Labs | Puppet
				Labs</title>
			<description>In the latest Puppet Podcast, Community team member Kara
				Sowles is joined by long-time Puppet developer Jeff McCune along
				with Cody Herriges and Matt Kirby from the technical operations
				Team.
				The engineering staff at Puppet Labs has been growing quickly, which
				has meant that a lot of development and testing infrastructure has
				had to adapt and change. It used to be feasible to have each
				developer test Puppet on either their own laptop or within a single
				testing infrastructure. But with Puppet supporting more and more
				operating systems, including AIX and Windows, it's no longer
				feasible for all the tests to happen locally. Having one QA
				environment that any developer can render useless also doesn't work
				too well at scale.
				So in this podcast, we explore how the development and operations
				teams at Puppet Labs are collaborating on a project to create more
				isolated virtual and physical test environments for each developer.
				This is enabling developers to be a bit more experimental and free
				to break things in their environment without worrying about slowing
				anyone else down.
				They're also coming up with a solution to eliminate all the time-consuming
				steps needed to get that space by creating a variety of self-service
				interfaces to different parts of their infrastructure.
				Their goal is to give new developers the ability to write a patch to
				Puppet code on their first day of work, then run it through their
				own QA environment that's optimized for continuous delivery. Jeff
				talks about how he able to interact with VMware's vSphere API using
				a combination of fog and the rbvmomi Ruby library.
				Jeff, Cody and Matt also talk about the some of their work building out
				software-defined infrastructure with a network virtualization layer.
				Tools like Razor, a bare-metal provisioning tool, are sometimes
				difficult to consistently test within the context of a laptop
				environment, and are much better tested within the VMware
				infrastructure maintained by operations. Some other challenges with
				Razor include changing the behavior of DHCP or PXE boot yourself
				while not interfering with other production environments or the
				primary wireless network. The group talks about implementing
				OpenStack's Neutron networking interface (formerly quantum) and
				VMware's NSX network in order to achieve this.
				Cody also talks about some specific considerations building an automated
				cloud infrastructure with dynamic storage capabilities. Specific
				considerations include creating a distributed storage architecture
				that eliminates the possibility of single-points of failure taking
				out the entire storage infrastructure for other virtual machines.
				There are also different optimizations for handling different heavy
				read vs. heavy write workloads, as well as hosting it within a
				private cloud or public cloud.
				One specific challenge involves gathering enough metrics to know both
				how to grow and when to expand capacity. Some of the tools being
				explored include setting up a Ceilometer infrastructure to collect
				measurements within OpenStack environments.
				Finally, the group talks about the process of designing and architecting a
				boundless infrastructure that is architected for scalability,
				reliability and elasticity; abstracted enough to plug in new
				capabilities in the future, yet stable enough that the ops team can
				sleep through the night.
				You can also check out our many other recent podcasts by visiting our
				podcast page or subscribing in your favorite podcast tool.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-devops-cloud-automation-puppet-labs</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode023-2013-11-06-Puppet-Labs-Tools-and-Process.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Project Management and DevOps | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>In this episode of the Puppet Labs Podcast, I was joined
				by Kenn Hussey, Michelle Johansen and Heidi Pio to talk about how
				project managers help bridge the gap between developers and
				operations.
				For example, our recent migration from Redmine to JIRA has required
				extensive collaboration between our developers and our operations
				teams across many months to make sure that we could complete the
				migration without disrupting work on our products.
				We also have quite a few cross-functional teams between engineering
				and operations,  pulled together to handle issues with developer
				infrastructure, security concerns and much more on an ad hoc basis.
				The Puppet Forge engineering team has a representative from our
				operations team who attends its meetings. Across all of our
				projects, we try to get operations involved at the very beginning of
				each project.
				For much more about project management and DevOps, please have a
				listen! You can also check our many other recent podcasts by
				visiting our podcast page or subscribing in your favorite podcast
				tool.
				If all of this sounds interesting and you want to join us, we are also
				hiring two new project managers, an Engineering Project Manager and
				a Technical Operations Project Manager. Come work with us, we have
				whiskey.
				Learn More
				Listen to our other podcasts.
				Join the Puppet Community.
				Follow our DevOps December content</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-project-management-and-devops</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode025-2013-12-17-Project-Management-and-DevOps.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Module Best Practices with Gareth Rushgrove | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>In this episode of the Puppet Labs Podcast, I was joined
				by Gareth Rushgrove, who works for the UK Government and is the
				person responsible for the DevOps Weekly Newsletter. He goes by
				garethr on the Puppet Forge. I was also joined by Ryan Coleman,
				product owner for the Forge at Puppet Labs.
				We talked about quite a few module best practices, with a focus on
				reusability of modules.  One important thing to keep in mind when
				designing reusable modules is how you abstract the data associated
				with modules and how you design the entry points for others. Using
				other people's modules as dependencies is another way to improve
				reusability, but you also need to make sure that your dependencies
				are solid, reliable modules.
				One of the most important aspects of module development is testing.
				Gareth and Ryan both talked about various ways to test your modules
				to improve reliability and check for unintended consequences when
				you make change to your module. Rspec-puppet is one good option for
				testing your modules if you are just getting started.
				To learn more about module best practices and reliability, you will
				need to listen to the podcast! You can also check our many other
				recent podcasts by visiting our podcast page or subscribing in your
				favorite podcast tool.
				Listen to our other podcasts.
				Join the Puppet Community.
				Watch Gareth's PuppetConf talk about Module Reusability or other great
				PuppetConf module talks.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/module-best-practices-gareth-rushgrove</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode027-2014-01-02-Module-Reusability.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Puppet Learning and Certification | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>In this episode of the Puppet Labs Podcast, I was joined
				by Greg Larkin, who talked to us about his experience preparing for
				and taking the Puppet Professional certification exam. I was also
				joined by two people from the Puppet Labs education team: Jamie
				Rosa, who runs our certification program, and Brad Hamilton, who
				recently launched the Puppet Workshop, our new online learning
				portal.
				We started by talking about our various certification exams, which are
				available at testing centers around the world. Greg became certified
				shortly after PuppetConf, and while he thinks that the best
				preparation is real-world Puppet implementation experience, he read
				a lot of documentation to help prepare for the exam. He also spent a
				lot of time answering questions on Ask.PuppetLabs.com — a great way
				to prepare for certification! Jamie also recommends reading the exam
				objectives and taking the practice exams, linked from the
				certification page.
				We recently launched the Puppet Workshop, where you can find free,
				online courses on many different topics. Each course takes about 20
				minutes to complete, and includes an instructional video, exercises
				and a quiz to test your knowledge. Right now, we have courses on a
				wide variety of topics about Puppet, PuppetDB, Hiera, modules, roles
				&amp; profiles, plus so much more. We are also adding new courses on
				a regular basis, so we'll have even more courses in the next few
				months.
				To get more information about our learning and certification programs,
				you should listen to the podcast! You can also check our many other
				recent podcasts by visiting our podcast page or subscribing in your
				favorite podcast tool.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-puppet-learning-and-certification</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode026-2013-12-18-Puppet-Certification.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Puppet at GitHub | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>In this podcast, Kent Bye and I talked with James Fryman
				and Will Farrington about the many ways that GitHub is using Puppet.
				We talked for quite a while about the creative ways that GitHub is
				using Boxen and Puppet to manage developer system configuration. I
				always think of Boxen as an easy way to quickly provision systems
				for new employees, but GitHub is doing some creative things with
				Hiera that makes it easy for people to maintain changes to their own
				configurations. It also helps to quickly roll out changes to
				everyone at the same time, like upgrades to a new version of Ruby,
				for example.
				Because it's been a hot topic recently, we also talked about the recent DNS
				outage at GitHub. They gave us a few more details about what
				happened, and what they are doing with Puppet and their own testing
				processes to avoid similar issues in the future.
				I won't ruin it by telling you too much more, so listen to the
				podcast to hear the rest! You can also check out our many other
				recent podcasts by visiting our podcast page or subscribing in your
				favorite podcast tool.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-puppet-github</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode028-2014-02-04-Puppet-at-GitHub.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: How To (and How Not To) Apply for a Tech Job | Puppet
				Labs</title>
			<description>Applying for a tech job? In the latest Puppet Podcast,
				we chat with Mike Stahnke, director of software delivery at Puppet
				Labs, and Deepak Giridharagopal, our director of engineering. Mike
				and Deepak certainly aren't short on work, yet they regularly take
				the time to review resumes for people who apply for positions in
				their departments. As technical managers who are also hiring
				managers, Mike and Deepak provided an interesting perspective for
				those currently applying to tech jobs.
				Hear tips for making your application stand out, extreme resume no-nos,
				and reflections on hiring from two of Puppet Labs' technical
				directors.
				You can also check our many other recent podcasts by visiting our
				podcast page or subscribing in your favorite podcast tool.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-how-and-how-not-apply-tech-job</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode029-2014-02-14-How-to-apply-for-a-tech-job.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Bare Metal Provisioning with Razor | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>Razor developers David Lutterkort and Scott McClellan
				talk about what Razor is, and how it compares to other provisioning
				tools. Razor does just the right amount of work to get an operating
				system installed onto a bare-metal machine so it can be further
				configured and managed by Puppet Enterprise.
				Razor has been rewritten from the ground up. David and Scott talk about
				the new features, as well as how it's being offered as a tech
				preview within Puppet Enterprise 3.2.
				You can participate in Razor and join the discussions in the #razor IRC
				channel and the Razor Google group.
				Listen in to learn about Razor’s new capabilities, and how you can provide
				feedback as you try it out. You can also check out our many other
				recent podcasts by visiting our podcast page or subscribing in your
				favorite podcast tool.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-bare-metal-provisioning-razor</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode030-2014-03-06-Razor-in-Puppet-Enterprise-32.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: The Puppet Language Evolves | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>I recently had the opportunity to sit down with Andy
				Parker and Henrik Lindberg to talk about some of the many upcoming
				changes to the Puppet language, which is our configuration language
				used to define resources (and more). We were joined by videographer
				Kent Bye, who also jumped in with a few of his own questions
				throughout the podcast.



				We talked about a wide range of language topics, but we spent a little
				more time on a few of the more interesting upcoming changes. Andy's
				favorite improvement to the language is our new and vastly improved
				error reporting, now with error messages that actually help you
				figure out what went wrong! We also talked a lot about the new type
				system, which is something Henrik is pretty excited about. Support
				for templates and Heredoc are among the many other topics we
				discussed, so listen to the podcast and get all the details!
				If you are as excited about these upcoming language features as Andy
				and Henrik, you can enable our experimental Future Parser and try
				them out now. If you aren't quite ready yet, you can still browse
				the Future Parser documentation to see what we are adding and how it
				will be used. You can also keep track of our progress and upcoming
				work by following the tickets filed under the DSL component in JIRA.
				Interested in joining the discussions about the future of the Puppet
				Language, or other development topics? You'll find those on the
				puppet-dev mailing list.
				If you enjoy this podcast about the Puppet language, you should check
				out our podcast page for more great discussions, or subscribe in
				your favorite podcast tool.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-puppet-language</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode031-2014-03-18-Puppet-Language.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast on Beaker: The cloud-enabled, acceptance testing tool
				| Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>Have you heard of Beaker yet? Beaker is a testing tool
				developed and used here at Puppet Labs. In this podcast, Puppet Labs
				QA toolsmith Alice Nodelman, community member Richard Pijnenburg,
				and Puppet Labs module engineer Hunter Haugen join videographer Kent
				Bye and community initiatives manager Kara Sowles to talk about what
				Beaker does and how you can benefit from it.
				Beaker is an acceptance-level testing tool that provisions a set of nodes
				to test on. Here at Puppet Labs, we can test Puppet on it, and we're
				also adopting it for automated module testing. Beaker can be used
				not only as an acceptance testing tool, but also as a cloud
				provisioner.
				Listen in to learn about the problems Beaker addresses, how to better
				automate your testing, how we're using Beaker internally at Puppet
				Labs, and what's next for the tool. Richard chimes in with his use
				of Beaker, what tools he's used to decrease his test time from
				5-plus hours to 45 minutes, and more details about his testing
				suite.
				You can check out our other recent podcasts by visiting our podcast
				page or subscribing in your favorite podcast tool!</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-beaker-cloud-enabled-acceptance-testing-tool</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode032-2014-04-10-Integrated-System-Testing-With-Beaker.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Insights from the Monitorama Conference | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>If you missed the recent Monitorama conference in
				Portland, highlighting the latest data monitoring technology, we’ve
				got you covered. Listen to Puppet Labs technical operations
				engineers Cody Herriges and Zach Leslie, technical operations
				project manager Derek Austin, community manager Kara Sowles and
				videographer Kent Bye discussing the conference in our most recent
				podcast.
				You can learn about the tools our employees find most useful for
				monitoring; areas they’d like to see fleshed out at next year's
				Monitorama; challenges for the data monitoring sector; and their
				favorite talks (Hint: math and frequencies are involved.). We’re
				sure you’ll find the information stimulating and useful.
				Meg Hartley is community coordinator at Puppet Labs.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-insights-monitorama-conference</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode034-2014-05-21-Monitorama.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast:Provisioning Hadoop Clusters With Cloudera Manager and
				Puppet | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>Cloudera fans, rejoice! In this week’s Puppet podcast,
				Kent Bye and I talked to Mike Arnold, author of the
				Cloudera-certified CDH module, now available on the Puppet Forge.
				The CDH module deploys part of the Cloudera management stack, which
				can then be used to deploy Cloudera's Hadoop distribution onto a
				system.

				Mike notes, "I know when I started four years ago it was, 'What's this
				Hadoop thing? What do you mean a Java-based file system, what's
				that?' It's been a great journey since then — things got very
				popular very quickly, and Hadoop seems to be on everyone's mind
				nowadays. It was a good way to add a skill set to my systems
				administrator cap that lets me do quite a lot of cool things with
				distributed clusters."
				Mike's put a lot of work into this impressive module, and it's great to
				hear him talk more about it. If you're interested in learning more
				about provisioning Hadoop clusters with Cloudera Manager and Puppet,
				this podcast's for you.
				You can find all of Mike's modules on the Puppet Forge under
				razorsedge.
				You can also check our many other recent podcasts by visiting our
				podcast page or subscribing in your favorite podcast tool.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/provisioning-hadoop-clusters-cloudera-manager-and-puppet</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode033-2014-05-05-Provisioning-Hadoop-Clusters-With-Cloudera-Manager-and-Puppet.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Getting Organized with Roles and Profiles | Puppet
				Labs</title>
			<description>
				If you need a way to manage a large and complex infrastructure and
				gather all the parts of your Puppet manifests together, then this
				week’s podcast is for you!
				Puppet Labs professional services engineer, James Sweeny, chats with
				Puppet certified Linux engineer, Greg Swift, about how he’s using
				the Roles and Profiles design model with much success at Rackspace.
				Don’t miss the conversation full of aha moments between James and
				Greg. (Even seasoned Puppet users will learn something new.)
				Hear Greg explain:</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-getting-organized-roles-and-profiles</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode036-2014-06-04-Roles-and-Profiles.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Product Management | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>Ever wondered what a product manager does every day?
				Then this podcast is for you. Kara Sowles and Meg Hartley from the
				Puppet Labs community department and videographer Kent Bye sat down
				with Lindsey Smith, product owner, and Susannah Axelrod, director of
				product management, to learn how product management works generally,
				and specifically at Puppet Labs.
				Susannah sums up the role of the product manager as, “We take a lightning
				strike and turn it into a more predictable machine.” Lindsey adds,
				“We’re able to think of things holistically."
				Susannah entered product management from the business and strategy side, and
				chose the tech industry for its constant innovation, while Lindsey,
				a self-taught software developer, took a more technical route.
				Lindsey goes on to say, "There’s a wide variety of strengths you can
				bring."
				As Susannah and Lindsey share the many paths to becoming a product
				manager, Susannah says, “One of the things that makes this job
				interesting is it’s accommodating to a wide range of skill sets, and
				you can find a place for yourself in that."

				Lindsey says his role is to represent all the people not in the room. He
				shares one of the many things that he’s found rewarding about
				working at Puppet Labs: “Twice in the last few months we’ve been
				able to talk to [kids in] computer science clubs about how software
				gets made."
				Product management is a growing field, and integral to the success of the
				product as a company scales. As Susannah says, “We’re able to look
				out over X months or years, and develop a road map and talk about
				the cadence of release.”
				Listen in to find out how Susannah and Lindsey go on to emphasize the ways
				they do that at Puppet Labs, plus:</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-product-management</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode035-2014-05-28-Product-Management-at-Puppet-Labs.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Puppet for Windows Sysadmins | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>In the latest edition of the Puppet Podcast, you’ll get
				the lowdown on tools and tips for Windows sysadmins using Puppet.
				Erin Buckley, senior instructional designer at Puppet Labs, shares
				the new online workshop courses she's been working on, which will
				provide tools to help Windows users navigate the Linux environment
				and shorten their Puppet ramp up time.
				Travis Fields and Ryan Gard, senior software engineer and SQA engineer,
				respectively at Puppet Labs, joined in to tell hosts Kara Sowles,
				community manager, and Kent Bye, video content marketer, about their
				past lives as Windows administrators. Travis and Ryan dispense
				advice to Windows administrators interested in Puppet, including
				helpful tools and resources to be aware of. We’ll discuss the best
				ways for Windows admins without prior Unix experience to prepare for
				Puppet Fundamentals training, and get started on their path to
				Puppet mastery!
				You can also check out our many other recent podcasts by visiting our
				podcast page or subscribing in your favorite podcast tool.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-puppet-windows-sysadmins</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode037-2014-06-25-Getting-Started-with-Windows-and-Puppet.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: The Word on PuppetDB 2.1.0 From Our Developers |
				Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>Want the details on what's new in PuppetDB 2.1.0, just
				released this week? Kara Sowles, community manager, and Kent Bye,
				video content marketer, sat down with software developers Ken Barber
				and Ryan Senior to chat about all of the new features in the 2.1.0
				release of PuppetDB.
				They’ve been hard at work on the new release and have lots to be excited
				about. Hint: this release is chock full of benefits for users.
				Ryan and Ken are especially excited about the query engine. "We've spent
				a lot of time fixing inconsistencies and expanding the things you
				can query," said Ryan. "From a maintenance perspective, it's a big
				win for our developers, and from the functionality perspective, it's
				a big win for PuppetDB users."
				Tune in for all this, plus little-known facts such as how PuppetDB got
				its name, and Spotify’s contributions to its development.
				We’ll answer these questions:
				Have a question or comment? Email us at podcast@puppetlabs.com.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-word-puppetdb-210-our-developers</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode038-2014-07-10-PuppetDB.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Docker &amp; Puppet: Uniting Containers with
				Configuration Management | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>Last week was OSCON week in Portland - and with OSCON,
				thousands of people from all over the world fly to our home city of
				Portland, Oregon, to talk tech. We were fortunate to book some time
				with the folks from Docker for a Puppet Podcast!
				On this week's Puppet Podcast, we welcome Jérôme Petazzoni and Aaron
				Huslage from Docker; Daniel Dreier, a local Puppet + Docker
				community member here in Portland; and Kylo Ginsberg, a Platform
				Engineer at Puppet Labs. As usual, Kara Sowles and Kent Bye from
				Puppet Labs hosted the conversation.
				Docker is an open source engine that runs and manages containers, which is
				a Linux kernel feature for providing lightweight virtualization at
				the operating system level. Containers are small, cheap, fast to
				start, and are starting to unlock new use cases for how
				infrastructure is architected.
				Daniel talks to us about his work at his web hosting business, and the
				three-step process that he’s using in order to separate and contain
				the users on his shared hosting platform. He’s using r10k and puppet
				apply command, in order to create a container with Puppet, and then
				he’s using a YAML file in order to do specific configuration within
				that container. Then, he’s deploying to CoreOS and storing secrets
				within the etc.d file. He talks about his experiences with blending
				Puppet configuration management with Docker containers, and what
				works well and where there’s room for improvement.
				Kylo addresses the intersection between Puppet and Docker, between
				configuration management and containers. He covers different ways
				people are using them together by either puppetizing Docker hosts,
				authoring docker images using Puppet, or by running Puppet within
				Docker containers in order to manage the state and configuration
				over time.
				Jerome and Aaron delve into some of the new use cases for containers that
				they’re seeing, as well as the blurred boundaries between virtual
				machines and containers and how exactly they fit together.
				For more information on working with containers and configuration
				management, be sure to sign up to listen to our Docker and Puppet
				webinar discussion between Docker’s James Turnbull and Puppet Labs’
				David Lutterkort &amp; Eric Shamow. They cover a number of more
				specific code snippets for puppetizing Docker hosts with Gareth
				Rushgrove’s Puppet module, authoring Docker images with Puppet
				either with or without a Puppet Master, and finally how to run
				Puppet within a container.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-docker-puppet-combining-containers-configuration-management</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode039-2014-07-30-Docker-Puppet.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Geppetto 4.2 – New and Improved | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>Have you used Geppetto? (Hint: it’s not Pinocchio’s
				creator.) Listen in to the Geppetto 4.2 edition of the Puppet
				Podcast to learn all about the latest release. Kent and Kara chat
				with Thomas Hallgren, the Puppet Labs engineer responsible for much
				of the work on 4.2.
				Geppetto is an IDE, interactive development environment, tailor-made for
				editing modules and Puppet manifests and publishing git modules from
				the Puppet Forge. Thomas tells us more about IDE's and what makes
				Geppetto superior to others.
				Geppetto can test your code as you create it. ”Geppetto keeps things live
				and runs builders to verify and link everything together and gives
				warnings. With Geppetto, you’ll have a Puppet ‘lint’ tool that’s
				running all the time and keeps a well defined model of everything
				that you’re editing in the workspace." Thomas explains.
				Thomas finds the documentation tool tips and code completion helpful in
				this release. He illustrates the objectives for Geppetto 4.2,
				including support for new module metadata attributes, the new text
				based editor for metadata.json, improved module validation, and
				more.
				Listen to find out:
				Send us your thoughts, ideas, questions: podcast@puppetlabs.com. (We
				love reading them!)</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-geppetto-42-new-and-improved</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode040-2014-08-27-Geppetto.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Automating Cumulus Network Gear with Puppet | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>Welcome to another week of the Puppet Podcast! This
				time, Kara Sowles and Kent Bye are joined by Sergey Sudakovich and
				Meena Sankaran of Cumulus Networks, and Kris Amundson, Senior SysOps
				Engineer at Puppet Labs. If you're into networking, listen in – this
				podcast is for you!
				Cumulus is doing some interesting things as they work to bring their own
				flavor of Linux to packet pushers. The Open Network Install
				Environment (ONIE) Project is the PXE equivalent for network devices
				– the glue that couples a minimal boot environment and software
				image management that gets bare ports to functional configured
				elements as part of a Zero Touch Provisioning strategy. With Linux
				on your networking gear, Puppet just got easier to begin managing
				networks.
				On this podcast, Sergey and Meena ask us to think about networking's
				place in DevOps. "Start thinking of networking more like the server
				industry adopts technology: where they could just buy a piece of
				hardware, install an OS, and then automate everything. That's the
				DevOps mentality and that's what we're trying to achieve with the
				new model of operations."
				Listen in to Cumulus's approach to the future of networking, as they
				explore how much automation can be enabled on the networking side
				and the importance of companies giving back to the community and to
				the open source tools that they use.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/automating-cumulus-network-gear-puppet</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode041-2014-09-03-Cumulus-Networks.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: CERN and Puppet | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>Our most recent Puppet Podcast is thrilling: a rare
				opportunity to talk with CERN about Puppet. Our special guest, Tim
				Bell, runs the IT infrastructure group at CERN. He's joined by
				Puppet Labs Platform Engineering Director Deepak Giridharagopal and
				hosts Kara Sowles and Kent Bye for a long talk on CERN's two-year
				infrastructure overhaul and what they're doing with Puppet.
				CERN, the European Organization for Nuclear Research, was founded in 1954
				as a research laboratory where scientists could gather for
				fundamental research. Tim tells us, "The basic goal is to understand
				the universe, how it works, and what it's made of. The aim is the
				quest for knowledge."
				The largest experiment they run is the Large Hadron Collider (LHC), the
				largest piece of scientific equipment on the earth, which is "used
				in order to recreate some of the conditions after the big bang and,
				by doing so, understand the fundamental particles of which matter is
				made." As you can imagine, these experiments are producing a massive
				amount of data. How do they record, store, and analyze it? Listen in
				to find out!
				CERN records 35 petabytes per year of data, and employs an army of
				servers trying to recognize patterns in the data. Tim talks to us
				about their 2 year upgrade and how they've reconstructed, in 18
				months, toolchains that previously took 10 years to prepare. We
				learn how they use Puppet and OpenStack together, how they manage
				their upgrades so that they're not disruptive, and how they have
				12,000 hosts divided into over 100 host groups.
				While Tim and his IT infrastructure group continue their work, the new
				LHC is being cooled to temperatures colder than outer space, and
				placed in a vacuum of ten times less pressure than on the moon.
				Listen to our podcast to find out how they're preparing for the
				petabytes of data it will produce!</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-cern-and-puppet</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode042-2014-09-05-CERN.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Most Valued Puppeteer Winners | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>Listen in to hear a special PuppetConf 2014 edition of
				the Puppet Podcast featuring the winners of the first annual,
				community-nominated Most Valued Puppeteer (MVP) Award. The winner
				and finalists of the MVP award, Erik Dalén, system engineer at
				Spotify, Tim Sharpe, sysadmin at GitHub, and Daniele Sluijters,
				Puppetboard module author, join Kara Sowles, Puppet Labs’ community
				manager, and Kent Bye, Puppet Labs’ video content marketer, to chat
				about their contributions to the community. Felix Frank, one of the
				finalists, was not at PuppetConf, so, unfortunately, could not be on
				the podcast.
				The voting for the award happened at the Contributor Summit by
				community members. The winner and three finalists were announced by
				Luke Kanies, Founder and CEO of Puppet Labs, during his keynote at
				PuppetConf 2014.
				The MVP award winner, Erik Dalén, wrote puppet-dbquery and
				puppet-explorer. Learn why he wrote them for his purposes at Spotify
				and how he regularly fixes bugs, specifically to Facter, Puppet core
				code, and PuppetDB. You’ll hear how Tim has used PuppetDB Query to
				make his job easier at GitHub and why Daenney says, “Integrating
				PuppetDB query support into Puppetboard has made it a lot easier to
				work with and query.”
				Tim Sharpe tells us all about the puppet-lint and rspec-puppet tools
				that he wrote. At the Contributor Summit, Mike Stahnke told the
				audience, “If you’re not running Puppet using the puppet-lint module
				then your stuff is not as good as it would otherwise be.” Find out
				how Daenney and Erik have used the Tim’s puppet-lint tool and why
				Daenney says, “I’d go insane and be throwing myself off a building
				without rspec-puppet.”
				Find out how Felix Frank became known as the one of the top contributors
				of all time in the puppet-user mailing list. “He has fixed a lot of
				long standing bugs,” says Erik. Listen in to find out which ones.
				Danielle (Daenney) Sluijters, tells us why he wrote the puppetboard
				module and what it can do for your infrastructure, about his work on
				the puppet-apt module and what he learned at PuppetConf from our
				community about his contributions.
				Want to know what our three contributors thought of the second
				Contributor Summit held at PuppetConf? Listen in to find out!
				We have lots of upcoming opportunities for you to contribute to the
				community and learn from others in person and online. #puppethack,
				our online community hack day, happens December 4th with a wide
				range of hours to reflect the variety of time zones that our
				community calls home. We also have our Puppet Contributor Summit EU
				in Ghent, Belgium on Feb 4, 2015. We hope to see you at one or both
				of these events or at an upcoming Puppet Camp!
				Have suggestions for future podcasts, questions or comments? Email us:
				podcast@puppetlabs.com.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-most-valued-puppeteerwinners</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode043-2014-10-10-Puppet-Most-Valuable-Puppeteer.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Node Manager | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>This week on the Puppet Podcast, Kara and Kent are
				joined by Dan Lidral-Porter and Justin Holguin, engineers at Puppet
				Labs, to talk about the Puppet Node Manager. We've been excited
				about the Puppet Node Manager since before Dan stood onstage during
				Luke Kanies' PuppetConf Keynote and demo'd it, so we're thrilled to
				have him on the Puppet Podcast to tell you about it. In this podcast
				Dan and Justin dive into how Node Manager simplifies managing a
				large number of frequently changing systems while using Puppet
				Enterprise.
				Puppet Node Manager is the first of the new Puppet Apps. With Puppet Node
				Manager, you can write rules based on the attributes of a node, and
				the rules will determine what that node should look like. You can
				manage your infrastructure based on each node's job, rather than
				name, without needing to manually classify each node.
				Dan and Justin go in-depth on how to troubleshoot and resolve node
				conflicts when using node manager, and reveal where the tool is
				headed next. If you haven't tried out Puppet Node Manager, we hope
				this inspires you to give it a try!</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-node-manager</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode044-2014-11-25-Puppet-Node-Manager.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Puppet Server | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>In this edition of the Puppet podcast, hosts, Kara
				Sowles and Kent Bye, interview Chris Price, one of the primary
				engineers working on Puppet Server here at Puppet Labs. We had a
				compelling conversation discussing the many aspects of Puppet Server
				that came out in the 3.7 Puppet Enterprise release, including how
				it's built on Trapperkeeper and why they chose to write it in
				Clojure.
				Puppet Server started out as weekend coding stints for Chris, and grew
				into a next generation replacement for the Puppet Master. Chris had
				the opportunity to demo Puppet Server during Puppet Labs CEO and
				Founder, Luke Kanies’ keynote at PuppetConf this September. He said,
				“It was one of the more interesting experiences that I’ve had in a
				long time.” Listen in to find out why!
				Chris tells us about Trapperkeeper (hint: It’s not a binder from the
				‘80’s) and how they decided to build it: “We spent a lot of time
				looking at things that exist already and found our needs were much
				simpler and felt we could write something in Clojure that would
				provide a better end user experience.” Get the goods on what
				Trapperkeeper makes available for Puppet Server, PuppetDB and other
				PE features like RBAC and node classification.
				Chris gave us so much great information. You’ll need to listen to find
				out the rest, including answers to the following:
				Are you intrigued? Chris welcomes suggestions and bug reports from the
				community. Also, feel free to find him on FreeNode under cprice404.
				If you enjoyed this podcast, you should check out our podcast page
				for more great discussions, or subscribe in your favorite podcast
				tool.
				Don’t forget to email us at podcasts@puppetlabs.com - we’d love to hear
				about future podcasts that you want to hear and any questions or
				concerns you have.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-puppet-server</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode045-2014-12-02-Puppet-Server.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Test-Driven Development | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>In this edition of the Puppet Podcast, hosts Kara and
				Kent sat down with Gareth Rushgrove, Puppet Labs software engineer,
				to talk about Test Driven Development (TDD). This podcast is
				especially helpful to those who are new to TDD: the process of
				writing tests first, then writing enough code to pass the test and
				finally refactoring the code to make it better.
				Gareth shares how he uses Test Driven Development and why he’s found it a
				compelling way to write code. He says, “Tests help you move quickly
				and not break functionality.” He encourages those new to TDD to jump
				in and write their first test. He explains,“Writing the first test
				is the hardest, but once you’ve gotten one test in, you can
				replicate that to different modules very easily.”
				Gareth recommends reading the code of modules that have test suites, such
				as garethr-docker and other Puppet Approved modules and to join the
				puppet-users mailing list if you’re just starting out writing tests.
				Be sure to check out the Learn More section below for even more
				resources.
				Want to know which tests to write, which tools and frameworks he
				recommends for different testing situations, how to get started with
				TDD, and more? Listen in!
				If you enjoyed this podcast, you should check out our podcast page for
				more great discussions, or subscribe in your favorite podcast tool.
				Don’t forget to email us at podcasts@puppetlabs.com - we’d love to
				hear about future podcasts ideas or questions you have.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-test-driven-development</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode046-2014-12-15-Test-Driven-Development.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: Automated Testing with Beaker for Windows | Puppet
				Labs</title>
			<description>In this edition of the Puppet Podcast, Kara and Kent sat
				down with Liam Bennett, infrastructure engineer at OpenTable, Alice
				Nodelman, Puppet Labs QE toolsmith responsible for Beaker, and Rob
				Reynolds, Puppet Labs software engineer and creator of Chocolatey to
				chat about acceptance testing with Beaker for Windows.
				Liam works heavily on Windows machines at OpenTable and he was using and
				contributing to rspec-puppet to make it compatible for Windows.
				After learning about Beaker on Twitter, he translated that work over
				to Beaker. Liam’s PowerShell work is already a part of Beaker, and
				more Windows native support will be landed in future releases of
				Beaker.
				Listen in to hear Liam, Alice and Rob discuss the limitations with testing
				Puppet on Windows, upcoming changes to Beaker, other ways of using
				Beaker and more.
				For those running tests on Beaker in a Windows environment, check out
				Liam’s three-part blog series on acceptance testing at OpenTable:
				Part 1: Configuring and Writing Tests;
				Part 2: The Story of How They Started Acceptance Testing on Windows;
				Part 3: How to use Beaker to test Puppet roles and profiles for both
				Linux and Windows.
				Get in touch with Liam on GitHub and@liamjbennett on Twitter.
				If you enjoyed this podcast, you should check out our podcast page for
				more great discussions, or subscribe in your favorite podcast tool.
				Don’t forget to email us at podcast@puppetlabs.com - we’d love to
				hear about future podcasts ideas or questions you have.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-automated-testing-beaker-windows</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode047-2014-12-16-Windows-Acceptance-Testing-with-Beaker.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Podcast: How to Contribute to the Puppet Core | Puppet Labs</title>
			<description>In this edition of the Puppet podcast, Kara and Kent sat
				down with Felix Frank, Puppet power user and systems engineer, and
				Josh Partlow, Puppet Labs software engineer, to chat about
				contributing to the Puppet core projects — primarily Puppet, Facter
				and Hiera. Felix is one of the top contributors of all time to the
				Puppet mailing lists and a Featured Community Member.
				Felix got started contributing to the Puppet Core projects by writing the
				first couple of Puppet patches for his employer. For folks new to
				contributing to Puppet core projects, Felix suggests, “For me, the
				best thing to start with was Puppet types and providers. It’s work
				that is quite obvious and palpable and straight-forward. You can get
				results fairly quickly.”
				Josh agrees that the Puppet types and providers extension is the best
				way to get started and what he sees mostly from the community. They
				go on to outline the entire process of contributing to the Puppet
				Core, including the most important and difficult pieces.
				Keep listening to hear Felix and Josh talk about how to write tests for
				your patches. Josh says,”Don’t be afraid to ask for help.” He goes
				on to give advice on the best ways to get that help.
				Felix talks about his new book, Puppet Essentials which he created for
				folks who are used to writing software or operating servers and want
				to get started using Puppet quickly. He goes on to talk about how it
				can help you ramp up on Puppet, how his book came to fruition and
				his stint in blogging.
				Find Felix on GitHub and check out his blog. Follow him on Twitter
				@felis_rex.
				If you enjoyed this podcast, you should check out our podcast page for
				more great discussions, or subscribe in your favorite podcast tool.
				Don’t forget to email us at podcast@puppetlabs.com — we’d love to
				hear about future podcasts ideas or questions you have.</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puppetlabs.com/podcasts/podcast-how-contribute-puppet-core</guid>
			<enclosure
				url="http://puppetcast.s3.amazonaws.com/puppetcast-episode048-2014-12-23-Contributing-to-Puppet.mp3"
				length="0" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>